Records of the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia; Law, Appellate, and Criminal Records; Case Papers 1802-1863
Center for Digital Research in the Humanities University of Nebraska–Lincoln
- Records of the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia; Law, Appellate, and Criminal Records; Case Papers 1802-1863
  - Civil Trials, 128-216, Negro John and Serena v. Henry Moscross; 1814, June; petition for freedom (see June term 1812, Civil Trial 253) (Box 69, Folder 202)
  - Civil Trials, 128-216, Negro Lucy and her children v. John & Nathan Somers; 1814, June; petition for freedom (Box 69, Folder 205)
  - Civil Trials, 128-216, Negro Rachel and her children v. Henry Jarvis; 1814, June; petition for freedom (Box 69, Folder 206)
  - Civil Trials, 128-216, Sally Henry v. Henry W. Ball; 1814, June; petition for freedom (Box 69, Folder 207)
  - Civil Trials, 128-216, Emanuel Gasbury v. Henry W. Ball; 1814, June; Petition for Freedom (Box 69, Folder 208)
  - Civil Trials, 128-216, "Violet a woman of Colour and her children" v. H.W. Ball; 1814, June; petition for freedom (Box 69, Folder 209)
  - Civil Trials, 128-216, John McCloud v. Esias Travers; 1814, June; Petition for Freedom; Plea of Trespass (Box 69, Folder 211)
  - Civil Trials, 128-216, John Bradley v. Pendleton Heronimus; 1814, June; Petition for Freedom (Box 69, Folder 214)
  - Appeals, Criminal Appeals, Criminal Trials, Imparlances, Judicials, 1-50, David Lenox v. Alexander S. Smoot; 1814, June; "1 negro man named Stephen aged about 34 years" $350.00 "1 negro man named Joseph aged about 26 years" $350.00 (Box 70, Folder 42)
  - Judicials, 51-144, 1814, June (Box 71)
  - Judicials, 146-203, 1814, June (Box 72)
  - Civil Appearances, 1-165, 1814, December (Box 73)
  - Civil Appearances, 176-404, 1814, December (Box 74)
  - Civil Trials, 5-160, 1814, December (Box 75)
  - Civil Trials, 162-247, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Priscilla Graham and her children v. Redmond Grace; 1814, December; petition for freedom; Black Washingtonians says "Gracey" (Box 76, Folder 247)
  - Imparlances, Judicials, 6-60, Bank of Washington v. Alexander Scott; 1814, December; "one yellow man named William" $3 50.00 (Box 77, Folder 22)
  - Judicials, 61-124, Appeal Bonds, Rough Bundle, Coroner’s inquests "Manuel a Coloured man...who died by the Visitation of God" "a Coloured man found in the Potomac unknown and the cause of his death unknown"; 1814, December (Box 78, Folder rough bundle)
  - Civil Appearances, 2-199, James Burk v. Coleman Lewis; 1815, June; petition for freedom; Not on Black Washingtonians (Box 79, Folder 18)
  - Civil Appearances, 2-199, Mary Prior v. Edward Coles; 1815, June; petition for freedom; Not on Black Washingtonians (Box 79, Folder 38)
  - Civil Appearances, 201-347, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, 1815, June (Box 80)
  - Civil Trials, 90-249, John A. Burford v. John Selby; 1815, June; Cause of suit: "You wickedly & maliciously attempting to persuade my black people to run away" (Box 81, Folder 184)
  - Civil Trials, 90-249, Negro Lucy and children v. Stephen Cooke; 1815, June; petition for freedom (Box 81, Folder 274)
  - Civil Trials, 255-285, Imparlances, Judicials, 1-41, 1815, June (Box 82)
  - Judicials, Petitions, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, 43-125, 1815, June; Coroner’s inquest on "a Negro boy named Bernard, belonging to the estate of the late John B. Rittenhouse, lying dead, at the shore of the River Potowmac, at Georgetown..., where he was found ﬂoating in the River by a certain Negro man, named Clement Shorter" (Box 83, Folder rough bundle)
  - Civil Appearances, 9-237, Thomas Foyle V. Washington Boyd; 1815, December; "one negro girl named Lotty" $300.00 (Box 84, Folder 112)
  - Civil Appearances, 9-237, Gerard Alexander v. —— Armsby; 1815, December; "one negro woman slave aged about 21 years and her infant child named Rosanna aged about one year both valued at $325.00" (Box 84, Folder 132)
  - Civil Appearances, 9-237, John Ball v. Mary Gatton; 1815, December; "one black boy named John about fifteen years old" $300.00 (Box 84, Folder 140)
  - Civil Appearances, 9-237, Adam Lindsay v. Thomas Davis; 1815, December; "one negro woman named Laura about forty years old" $200.00 "One negro child named Anne about ﬁve years old" 75.00 (Box 84, Folder 177)
  - Civil Appearances, 240-455, Civil Trials, 12-68, Nancy D. Hewitt v. Bennett Smith; 1815, December; "One Negro girl named Rachel about ﬁfteen years of age" $250.00 (Box 85, Folder 241)
  - Civil Appearances, 240-455, Civil Trials, 12-68, Cordelia Wilson v. [blank] Brown; 1815, December; petition for freedom (Box 85, Folder 414)
  - Civil Appearances, 240-455, Civil Trials, 12-68, Rosanna Brown V. [blank] Bennett; 1815, December; petition for freedom (Box 85, Folder 415)
  - Civil Appearances, 240-455, Civil Trials, 12-68, John Parker v. [blank] Offutt; 1815, December; petition for freedom (Box 85, Folder 416)
  - Civil Trials, 70-176, Charles Minifee v. Ambrose White; 1815, December; "two Negro Boys (Frederick & Hanson) sold...at one year’s credit" $600.00 (Box 86, Folder 83)
  - Civil Trials, 70-176, Charles Minifee v. John A. Burford; 1815, December; "Negroes David & Nancy" $400.00 (Box 86, Folder 84)
  - Civil Trials, 180-299, 1815, December (Box 87)
  - Civil Trials, 303-329, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, U.S. v. John Allen; 1815, December; "free negro...for stealing a Pocket Book containing ninety or ninety ﬁve dollars two Tobacco Notes and a note of Hand of James Johnston for 100 dollars" (Box 88, Folder 69)
  - Civil Trials, 303-329, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Negro Delia and children v. Thomas Offutt; 1815, December; petition for freedom (Box 88, Folder 69)
  - Imparlances, Judicials, 1-88, Thomas W. Pairo v. Francis Jenkins; 1815, December; "one Negro boy about 20 years old named John" $350.00 (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - Judicials, 90-169, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, J. Harding v. B. & E. Perry; 1815, December; "one young negro man named George about 25 years" $400.00 (Box 90, Folder 125)
  - Judicials, 90-169, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, J. Harding v. B. & E. Perry; 1815, December; "one young negro man named George about 25 years" $400.00 (Box 90, Folder 125)
  - Judicials, 90-169, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, 1815, December; Grand Jury "representation respecting James French..., a retailer of spirituous liquors, keeps a very disorderly house—particularly on the sabbath day, when there are large and tumultuous meetings, at his house, of negroes, and worthless whitemen— That the slaves in the neighborhood are corrupted by means of such meetings and practices..." (Box 90, Folder rough bundle)
  - Judicials, 90-169, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, 1815, December; Coroner’s inquests on "Jonathan 21 Coloured Boy" and "Bill a Coloured Man [who] died suddenly by the Earth falling on him where he was dig[g]ing" (Box 90, Folder rough bundle)
  - Civil Appearances, 1-132, 1816, June (Box 91)
  - Civil Appearances, 136-322, 1816, June (Box 92)
  - Civil Appearances, 334-515, 1816, June (Box 93)
  - Civil Trials, 1-139, 1816, June (Box 94)
  - Civil Trials, 144-200, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, U.S. v. William Ennis; 1816, June; "free mulatto," for stealing "nine pieces of pork of the value of eight dollars" (Box 95, Folder 35)
  - Civil Trials, 144-200, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, U.S. v. Ned Johnson; 1816, June; "free negro," for stealing four fence rails worth forty cents (Box 95, Folder 39)
  - Imparlances, Judicials, 1-55, 1816, June (Box 96, Folder 39)
  - Judicials, 57-130, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, 1816, June; John Brown’s certificate of freedom and character reference, in "miscellaneous" ﬁle (Box 97, Folder rough bundle)
  - Judicials, 57-130, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, "Case of Negro Morris"; 1816, June; Peter Morris’ petition for freedom; see also December term 1816, Civil Trial 336, and June term 1817, Civil Trial 360.; Black Washingtonians says "Morris Peers" (Box 97, Folder rough bundle)
  - Civil Appearances, 1-168, 1816, December (Box 98)
  - Civil Appearances, 185-417, 1816, December (Box 99)
  - Civil Appearances, 418-679, 1816, December (Box 100)
  - Civil Trials, 1-160, 1816, December (Box 101)
  - Civil Trials, 162-264, 1816, December (Box 102)
  - Civil Trials, 266-341, Criminal Appearances, Negro Morris v. George Miller; 1816, December; petition for freedom (Box 103, Folder 336)
  - Civil Trials, 266-341, Criminal Appearances, William Ethington v. William Crawford; 1816, December; petition for freedom (Box 103, Folder 338)
  - Criminal Trials, Imparlances, 1816, December (Box 104)
  - Judicials, Appeals, Coroner's Inquests, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, 1816, December; Richard Contee, "a coloured man...died suddenly...no marks of violence to be seen..." (Box 105, Folder Inquests)
  - Judicials, Appeals, Coroner's Inquests, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, 1816, December; "Col. Liles man Billy...being in a state of intoxication and out of doors and overcame by cold" (Box 105, Folder Inquests)
  - Civil Appearances, 1-101, Adam Bailey v. Philip Contee; 1817, June; petition for freedom (Box 106, Folder 20)
  - Civil Appearances, 103-202, William Washington v. Philip Contee; 1817, June; petition for freedom (Box 107, Folder 198)
  - Civil Appearances, 204-430, 1817, June (Box 108)
  - Civil Appearances, 431-520, 1817, June (Box 109)
  - Civil Appearances, 521-696, 1817, June (Box 110)
  - Civil Appearances, 698-938, 1817, June (Box 111)
  - Civil Trials, 7-189, 1817, June (Box 112)
  - Civil Trials, 7-189, 1817, June (Box 112)
  - Civil Trials, 192-297, 1817, June (Box 113)
  - Civil Trials, 301-360, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Imparlances, Appeal Bonds, Negro Cato v. Thomas Olfutt, Jr.; 1817, June; petition for freedom (Box 114, Folder 351)
  - Civil Trials, 301-360, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Imparlances, Appeal Bonds, Peter Morris v. J. Davis & J. Kincaid; 1817, June; petition for freedom (see also June term 1816, Rough Bundle); Black Washingtonians says Morris Peer (Box 114, Folder 360)
  - Judicials, 1-128, 1817, June (Box 115)
  - Judicials, 130-168, Presentments, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Darky Johnson; 1817, June; "free negress" for stealing "a ham of Bacon" worth one dollar (Box 116, Folder 20)
  - Judicials, 130-168, Presentments, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Thomas Brown; 1817, June; "free negro" for stealing "one pair of pantaloons and one ﬂannel shirt" worth seven dollars (Box 116, Folder 21)
  - Judicials, 130-168, Presentments, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, US. v. Nat Dark; 1817, June; "free negro" for stealing an axe and a turkey, together worth $2 (Box 116, Folder 23)
  - Judicials, 130-168, Presentments, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. John Sims; 1817, June; "free negro" for stealing a pistol worth one dollar (Box 116, Folder 24)
  - Judicials, 130-168, Presentments, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, 1817, June; Susan Johnston’s certiﬁcate of freedom, in "miscellaneous" file (Box 116, Folder rough bundle)
  - Civil Appearances, 1-272, 1817, December (Box 117)
  - Civil Appearances, 274-513, S. Walker v. J .R. Edmonston & N. Moore; 1817, December; "one negro woman named Monica," worth $150 (Box 118, Folder 447)
  - Civil Appearances, 517-789, 1817, December (Box 119)
  - Civil Appearances, 791-1008, Mary Speake v. Walter Clarke; 1817, December; apparently has to do with a family: man Richard (Valued at $200), woman Sarah ($180), boy Frank ($250), girl Rachel ($200) and girl Alsey ($150); at sale, Rachel actually brought $216 and Alsey, $192. (Box 120, Folder 812)
  - Civil Trials, 6-242, 1817, December (Box 121)
  - Civil Trials, 247-335, Ann Queen v. Washington Boyd; 1817, December; "Mulatto girl Catharine aged ﬁﬁeen" $350 (Box 122, Folder 281)
  - Civil Trials, 337-446, Appeal Bonds, Coroner's Inquests, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, Joe & Nelly Thompson and Sarah their infant v. Walter Clarke; 1817, December; petition for freedom (Box 123, Folder 446)
  - Imparlances, 3-420, 1817, December (Box 124)
  - Imparlances, 422-567, Judicials, 1-93, 1817, December (Box 125)
  - Judicials, 95-187, Joseph Clark v. Walter Beale; 1817, December; "one negro man named Moses About 27 years old" $150 (Box 126, Folder 142)
  - Civil Appearances, 2-172, 1818, June (Box 127)
  - Civil Appearances, 2-172, Clementson & Joucherez v. Forrest; 1818, June; "one Negro man called James" $200.00 (Box 127, Folder 54)
  - Civil Appearances, 174-397, Henry McPherson v. George Miller; 1818, June; medical care for "a negro man slave named John" (Box 128, Folder 163)
  - Civil Appearances, 174-397, Charles B. Robinson v. John W. Bronaugh; 1818, June; "treating seven negroes" for typhoid fever (14 pounds, four shillings, sixpence=$28.33 1/3 [?]) (Box 128, Folder 345)
  - Civil Appearances, 409-697, 1818, June (Box 129)
  - Civil Appearances, 717-964, Civil Trials, 12-99, 1818, June (Box 130)
  - Civil Trials, 101-239, 1818, June (Box 131)
  - Civil Trials, 241-309, 1818, June (Box 132)
  - Civil Trials, 310-399, 1818, June (Box 133)
  - Civil Trials, 402-475, 1818, June (Box 134)
  - Civil Trials, 476-549, 1818, June (Box 135)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Imparlances, 1-75, U.S. V. Stephen Potter; 1818, June; "for aiding and asisting a certain slave, by the name of William,...in making his escape from his master...; for forging an instrument of writing, and furnishing the said William therewith, by which he, the said William, passed as a free man of color..." (This ﬁle also contains the runaway advertisement, clipped from a newspaper.) (Box 136, Folder 80)
  - Imparlances, 77-559, Appeals, 1818, June (Box 137)
  - Judicials, 1-115, 1818, June (Box 138)
  - Judicials, 117-224, John Tayloe v. William Grayson; 1818, June; Jack aged 58, $150; Agnes, 52, $50; Nell, 17, $400 (Box 139, Folder 136)
  - Recognizances, Rough Bundle, John Tayloe's checks, 1818, June; Coroner’s inquest on "a coloured lad by the name of Moses," a slave of Martin T. Gilbert, accidentally drowned in the Potomac (Box 140, Folder rough bundle)
  - Civil Appearances, 1-185, Jane H. Slocum v. Peter Griffin; 1818, December; "negro slave named Mary aged about" 27; Charlotte, 6; Harrison, 4, all seized for debt (Box 141, Folder 161)
  - Civil Appearances, 1-185, T.O. Williams v. R. & T. Beall; 1818, December; "negro woman named Letty?’ (replevin) (Box 141, Folder 162)
  - Civil Appearances, 189-471, Job Smith v. Edward Mattingly; 1818, December; "one Negro Boy James," age 9, $300.00 (Box 142, Folder 363)
  - Civil Appearances, 189-471, James Smith v. Job Smith; 1818, December; "negro boy named James about nine years of age" (pretty obviously the same child in both cases; another instance of the use of slaves as counters in lawsuits) (Box 142, Folder 413)
  - Civil Appearances, 478-663, Josias Simpson v. T.R. Smith; 1818, December; "one Mulatto Man called James" $700.00 (Box 143, Folder 509)
  - Civil Appearances, 478-663, C.W. Goldsborough v. J.C. Hutchinson; 1818, December; use of Goldsborough’s schooner Shamrock to bring a "load of slaves" from "Mattox Creek" to Baltimore, $130, from Mattox Creek to the Washington Navy Yard, $75. (Box 143, Folder 566)
  - Civil Appearances, 478-663, Samuel Bias v. John Rose; 1818, December; petition for freedom (Box 143, Folder 611)
  - Civil Appearances, 666-971, 1818, December (Box 144)
  - Civil Appearances, 873-1221, 1818, December (Box 145)
  - Civil Trials, 6-193, William Baker v. Gerard Gibson; 1818, December; Doctor’s bill for $33.00, most of which seems to have involved treating slaves, as: "Calomel for little negro," at 50 cents a time. (Box 146, Folder 6)
  - Civil Trials, 6-193, Jenny Thompson v. Joseph Clarke; 1818, December; petition for freedom (Box 146, Folder 76)
  - Civil Trials, 6-193, James Thompson v. Electius Spalding; 1818, December; petition for freedom (Box 146, Folder 77)
  - Civil Trials, 6-193, James Butler v. Electius Spalding; 1818, December; petition for freedom (Box 146, Folder 78)
  - Civil Trials, 195-293, Francis Lowndes v. John Potts; 1818, December; "hire of a negro boy" $50/year (Box 147, Folder 265)
  - Civil Trials, 296-388, 1818, December (Box 148)
  - Civil Trials, 391-494, James Piper v. John Chalmers; 1818, December; "hire of 4 negro men in his rope walk 264 days" $264 (Box 149, Folder 410)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Appeal Bonds, US. v. John Frazier; 1818, December; for "assault and battery on the body of David Hall, a black man the property of Washington Boyd...." (Box 150, Folder 2)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Appeal Bonds, U.S. v. Matilda & Eleanor Brown; 1818, December; "for retailing spirituous liquors to slaves minors & other persons on Sundays & other days without having a license" (Box 150, Folder 26)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Appeal Bonds, U.S. v. Dennis Edmonston; 1818, December; for "assault & Battery on the body of Harry, a negro slave the property of William Worthington..." (Box 150, Folder 39)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Appeal Bonds, U.S. v. Edward Johnston; 1818, December; "a colored man, for an assault and battery on the body of Rezin B. Of’futt...." (Box 150, Folder 51)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Appeal Bonds, U.S. v. James Carter; 1818, December; "a free yellow man, for an Assault & Battery on the body of [blank] a slave the property of Jesse Sims..." (Box 150, Folder 64)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Appeal Bonds, U.S. v. Kitty Jenkins; 1818, December; "free negress," for stealing "a ten dollar note" (Box 150, Folder 81)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Appeal Bonds, U.S. v. Ann Thomas; 1818, December; "free negress," "for stealing a wig worth $25" (Box 150, Folder 83)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Appeal Bonds, U.S. v. Edward Johnson; 1818, December; "free negro," "for stealing l2 ‘/2 yards domestic Cotton" ($5.00) (Box 150, Folder 85)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Appeal Bonds, U.S. v. Offey Rounds; 1818, December; "free negro," for stealing two chickens (50 cents) (Box 150, Folder 87)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Appeal Bonds, U.S. v. Elzey Kindle; 1818, December; "ree mulatto," for stealing forty dollars (Box 150, Folder 88)
  - Imparlances, 1818, December (Box 151)
  - Judicials, 2-109, 1818, December (Box 152)
  - Judicials, 111-241, Robert Brent v. Pendleton Heronimus; 1818, December; "One dark Mulatto Girl named Betty Thomas who has from 4 to 8 years to serve not exactly known to us, the terms of service" $100.00 "1 Mulatto man named Jere Campbell" $500.00 "one Negro Girl named Clarissa" $350.00 (Box 153, Folder 222)
  - Judicials, 243-301, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, 1818, December (Box 154)
  - Civil Appearances, 3-222, 1819, June (Box 155)
  - Civil Appearances, 224-464, 1819, June (Box 156)
  - Civil Appearances, 478-775, 1819, June (Box 157)
  - Civil Appearances, 778-1310, 1819, June (Box 158)
  - Civil Trials, 21-289, 1819, June (Box 159)
  - Civil Trials, 292-424, 1819, June (Box 160)
  - Civil Trials, 426-589, 1819, June (Box 161)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Criminal Papers, Appeal Bonds, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Alexander Reynolds; 1819, June; "a colored man, for stealing some mahogany wood and maple" worth $2.00 (Box 162, Folder 7)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Criminal Papers, Appeal Bonds, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Joseph Washington; 1819, June; "a colored man, for an assault and battery on Joseph Pebine, by whipping him with a cow-hide...." (Box 162, Folder 16)
  - Imparlances, 1819, June (Box 163)
  - Judicials, 1-102, 1819, June (Box 164)
  - Judicials, 104-241, 1819, June (Box 165)
  - Civil Appearances, 4-195, 1819, December (Box 166)
  - Civil Appearances, 199-312, 1819, December (Box 167)
  - Civil Appearances, 314-512, 1819, December (Box 168)
  - Civil Appearances, 527-795, 1819, December (Box 169)
  - Civil Appearances, 801-1187, 1819, December (Box 170)
  - Civil Appearances, 1191-1506, 1819, December (Box 171)
  - Civil Trials, 17-415, Lynch Wormly v. Smith Cock; 1819, December; petition for freedom; Black Washingtonians says "Luke Wormley" (Box 172, Folder 30)
  - Civil Trials, 417-528, 1819, December (Box 173)
  - Civil Trials, 530-649, 1819, December (Box 174)
  - Civil Trials, 651-906, 1819, December (Box 175)
  - Imparlances, 4-322, 1819, December (Box 176)
  - Imparlances, 326-808, 1819, December (Box 177)
  - Judicials, 2-116, 1819, December (Box 178)
  - Judicials, 118-238, 1819, December (Box 179)
  - Judicials, 243-276, Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. John B. Butler; 1819, December; "a free Negro, for an assault & Battery on...Joab Blakeman" (Box 180, Folder 22)
  - Judicials, 243-276, Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Rough Bundle, US. v. John B. Butler; 1819, December; "for an assault & Battery on...Samuel Gregory" (Box 180, Folder 23)
  - Judicials, 243-276, Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Thomas Riker; 1819, December; "(a Black man) for stealing a pair of shoes" worth $2.00 (Box 180, Folder 44)
  - Civil Appearances, 4-166, 1820, June (Box 181)
  - Civil Appearances, 169-355, 1820, June (Box 182)
  - Civil Appearances, 358-657, Henry Drain v. Charles C. Sears; 1820, June; household goods $ 73.50 included "one negro woman named Sarah" valued at $50.00 (Box 183, Folder 358)
  - Civil Appearances, 659-974, 1820, June (Box 184)
  - Civil Appearances, 985-1183, 1820, June (Box 185)
  - Civil Trials, 13-623, F. & T. Jenkins v. J. Wheaton & J. Dove; 1820, June; the Jenkinses have "taken and unjustly detain... one negro man slave named Lewis" (Box 186, Folder 14)
  - Civil Trials, 13-623, 1820, June; "William Green’s Release to Mrs. Sayres... the recovery of the freedom of a Certain Negro Clara and her children" (has to do with Clara’s petition for freedom from Thomas Ewell) (Box 186, Folder 26)
  - Civil Trials, 13-623, Negro Arnold v. George N. Thomas; 1820, June; petition for freedom (Box 186, Folder 251)
  - Civil Trials, 625-707, Richard T. Semmes v. William Sedwick; 1820, June; cloth $ 950.61 the bill includes "hire of negro Lucy" for $10.00 (Box 187, Folder 694)
  - Civil Trials, 710-820, 1820, June (Box 188)
  - Civil Trials, 824-908, 1820, June (Box 189)
  - Civil Trials, 910-1005, 1820, June (Box 190)
  - Civil Trials, 1011-1121, 1820, June (Box 191)
  - Appeal Bonds, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Presentments, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Negro Thomas Miles; 1820, June; arson (Box 192, Folder 26)
  - Appeal Bonds, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Presentments, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Negro Thomas Miles; 1820, June; arson (Box 192, Folder 26)
  - Appeal Bonds, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Presentments, Rough Bundle, John Allen; 1820, June; "free negro" for stealing clothing worth $22 (Box 192, Folder 3, 5)
  - Appeal Bonds, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Presentments, Rough Bundle, William Davis; 1820, June; "free negro" for stealing cloth worth $16 (Box 192, Folder 4)
  - Appeal Bonds, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Presentments, Rough Bundle, George Shorter; 1820, June; "free negro" for stealing clothing worth $50 (Box 192, Folder 6)
  - Appeal Bonds, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Presentments, Rough Bundle, Harry Hanson; 1820, June; "free mulatto" for stealing a silver watch worth $10 (Box 192, Folder 7)
  - Appeal Bonds, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Presentments, Rough Bundle, Bill Hollard; 1820, June; "free mulatto" for stealing clothing worth $3 (Box 192, Folder 13A)
  - Appeal Bonds, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Presentments, Rough Bundle, William Thompson & Benjamin Bridges; 1820, June; for "harboring a runaway slave" (Box 192, Folder 13B)